let's look at the solution to our
multiple prediction squeeze branches our
result in the third stage which means
that we will fetch this branch and then
we will fetch this and then we will
fetch this and at that point this branch
will be here and be resolved so we will
cancel this in this instruction and
start fetching from X and then Y so
overall we have wasted two cycles note
that this penalty here is the same as if
the second instruction here was not a
branch at all so basically here we
actually miss predicted two branches but
the second one was miss predicted in the
shadow of the first miss prediction this
branch would never have been fetched if
we predicted this correctly however the
penalty is unaffected so when we miss
predict a branch we just need to worry
about getting on the correct path and we
pay a penalty for that but we don't pay
additional penalties for miss predicted
branches that themselves should never
have been executed because of miss
predictions let's see why this is so it
is because the first branch here results
in flushing the pipeline when it gets to
the stage where branches are resolved
the branch that was fetched after it is
at that time here and the instruction a
is here and what now happens is we flush
the pipeline by converting these two
into pipeline bubbles and next cycle we
will be fetching X so what happens is
really if a branch has been fetched in
error because of a previous miss
prediction that branch never gets a
chance to cause a pipeline flush because
it itself gets flushed before that and
that's why we had a two cycle penalty
and not four cycles of penalty because
technically these two were miss
predicted but really this one should
never have been executed in the first
place but this one was flashed before
it could trigger a flash of its own